This is Minecraft, the game that screwed
its community so hard that we're about
to sue them in a class action lawsuit.
You see, in December of 2024, I uploaded
this video in which I exposed Mojang,
the creators of Minecraft, for breaking
consumer protection laws and exposing
children to gambling. And while I tried
to seek justice for myself, I wasn't
able to do so. Because my government is
kind of incompetent, making access to
justice basically impossible if you're
not rich as [ __ ] So, I tried adding a
GoFundMe campaign at the end to finance
a class action lawsuit because this
wasn't something that affected just me.
And obviously there's no way that would
actually work, right?
>> YouTube and suing Mo
already nearly on a million on trending
right now. Completed it already for
$120,000.
No way to pass.
>> That's got to be one of the fastest
growing crowdfunding campaigns.
>> We raised $150,000 within days.
>> Oh, it's [ __ ] happening. Where we now
have access to legal representation and
can proceed with the class action
lawsuit.
>> Yes, my name is Bjon Pasha. I'm a member
of the Swedish Bor Association. I run a
law firm together with my colleague law
and we're working with this lawsuit
since it's part of our practice and are
looking to um run this lawsuit as a
class action against Muya because we
think it's an important issue that needs
to be addressed. To give you a little
recap, Minecraft is one of those games
that anyone can modify to add things
that it didn't originally have. And what
I wanted to do was add guns to the game
to recreate an old game mode that I used
to play as a child that had
unfortunately been shut down. But right
as it was about to release, Mojang said
that a recent directive from Mojang
leadership determined that guns and
weapons are considered non-compliant
features, meaning that they had to be
completely removed, implying the
shutdown of dozens of projects,
including mine. But when actually
looking into it, even though they said
that guns and weapons were specifically
prohibited by the game's legal
agreement, when actually looking for
these specific prohibitions, you'd come
to find that they didn't actually exist.
So Mojang was making [ __ ] up and
pretending it was part of the terms of
service, a type of contract, which, as
you've guessed, is kind of illegal. A
contract is an agreement between two
parties and both parties need to agree
what the meaning of the contract is. You
can't be forced into new rules that
apply to your contract unless you've
been notified as well as having a choice
whether to actually accept those terms
or just be able to keep using what you
already have. And since this is a hidden
clause where guns are just one of the
many examples that exist, Mojang can do
whatever they want, like applying a
different version of the same clause
where you never know which one you're
going to get. changing their minds at
any time, like they did with the guns
three times, and even go against their
own rules, like allowing gambling even
though they publicly pretend like it's
forbidden. But obviously, [ __ ] gets
worse because when a company changes its
terms of service, it's required to
notify its users about the changes and
get their agreement for it. And out of
the 47 times they changed their legal
agreements, they never told anyone about
it. We know this because I went through
thousands of archived pages for every
single legal agreement that the game has
ever had to see if a single word had
changed. and Mojang not notifying anyone
of changes makes perfect sense since in
their own words it is up to you to check
back to see if these guidelines have
changed so that it's not their
responsibility to tell you there's a lot
of things that you really can't do with
the contract and have it enforceable
against the consumers you have this
legislation under European consumer law
that mandates that the company that
changes terms need to inform the
consumers about this and they can't
enforce the new changes without giving
the consumers a choice
>> and if without telling anyone who wasn't
already bad enough.
>> They removed the notice when software
tones were updated. This is obviously
making it harder for the consumers to
exercise their rights
>> because not only is it our
responsibility to check when changes
happen, but they also make it borderline
impossible to tell when they actually
did. Which is quite ironic coming from
the company that says, "We are trying to
be open, honest, and most importantly
trusting."
>> But of course, it only gets worse.
Remember how the original email from
Mojang said that guns were specifically
prohibited by these three legal
agreements? or one of them didn't even
exist. This is something I even pointed
out in the last video. By the Mojang
brand guidelines, guidelines that
literally do not exist. Well, it turns
out that they do exist as its own hidden
internal document under strict NDA that
does contain the prohibitions for guns.
The very same document where Mojang
internally recognizes loot boxes as
gambling. And what pisses me off even
more than them trying to apply a
contract that was literally impossible
to access without whistleblowers was
that while they left us on hold for 6
months because their CEO was on
vacation, they officially partnered with
Nerf, the gun company. Even though these
guidelines say that gunlike toys are
forbidden, [ __ ] hypocrites. But as
you probably guessed it, it only gets
worse. You see, when buying Minecraft,
you create a Mojang account that is then
used to play the game. At least that's
how it used to be because Mojang was
bought by Microsoft in 2014 where just a
few years later Mojang would announce
that we've decided that moving forward
all of our games will require a
Microsoft account to play. And if you
didn't want to migrate your account, you
won't be able to log in anymore, which
means you won't be able to play either.
In other words, either migrate your
account and give Microsoft all of your
data or they take away what you paid
for. And this is what you call a threat.
But not only did they threaten everyone,
they also sneakily modified their terms
of service to give themselves permission
to cancel your account if they simply
felt like it. And you see, when
purchasing a game like Minecraft, that
essentially means that you purchase a
license to download and play the game
where the conditions of that license are
within the terms of service. This is
important because if a company wanted to
change the way a service works by, for
example, changing their terms of
service, that new version would only
apply to the new users or the ones that
explicitly agreed to the changes. In
simple terms, if the contract used to
say that you will be able to play the
game, if the company doesn't like that
anymore, they can't take it away from
you because that would be called breach
of contract, which is kind of illegal.
And what happened here was that Mojang
was forcing everyone to migrate, saying
things like, "You will not be able to
access the game. Migration is mandatory.
Won't be able to play Minecraft. Must be
migrated to a Microsoft
>> Players need to move to a Microsoft
>> Mojang accounts to Microsoft accounts."
>> Where funnily enough, they had the balls
to say that this was voluntary three
times. So voluntary in fact that if you
didn't do it, they took away what you
paid for.
>> This was a forced migration where you
obviously didn't have much of a choice.
The only choice you had was to terminate
your account.
>> And not only were they forcing everyone
to give their data to a company with a
world record of privacy violations,
which got recently fined to $20 million
by the FTC for illegally collecting
information on children. Most Minecraft
players are children. But in doing so,
they also forced you to agree to
Microsoft and Xbox's legal agreements.
fall under the threat of them taking
away what you paid for if you didn't do
what they wanted.
>> A contract needs to be entered into
freely and that obviously means that you
need to have a choice between agreeing
and not agreeing. Just presenting one
choice is not really an agreement. But
even though it was illegal, Mojang still
went ahead with it, which resulted in
millions of people losing access to what
they paid for. Some of which were never
even notified that it was happening to
begin with, only finding out years later
that their purchase had been nullified.
But when actually contacting Mojang to
complain, you'd come to find that they
wouldn't answer questions and
automatically close most tickets asking
for answers. And when asking Microsoft
about it, they would say that, "I've
discussed your issue with Mojang support
and came to the conclusion that the
migration is within the Minecraft terms
and conditions." In other words, we've
investigated ourselves and found nothing
wrong. But unfortunately for them, this
user knows his rights. And when asking
Microsoft to site his contract for where
it says that a Microsoft account is
required to play, Microsoft said, "And
end user license agreements are
constantly updated. Please refer to the
current one where the current one says
if you originally signed up for a Mojang
account, you must migrate to a Microsoft
account in order to keep using the
services. But this wasn't part of the
contract when the user had bought the
game. To which Microsoft replied, I
understand that this is your
interpretation, but this ULA applies for
any user regardless of the date of
creation. Further stating that your
contract is the new ULA. The old one
doesn't apply anymore. You agreed to
these terms by using the service where
they then immediately close the ticket
refusing to answer any further
questions. This is a perfect example of
[ __ ] up in writing because it
confirms the idea that it is up to you
to check back to see if these guidelines
have changed and that they don't care
about agreements since they claim that
you agreed to changes that they didn't
even tell you about. So Mojang voided
everyone's contract since they say that
they don't apply anymore. And you
[ __ ] guessed it, this is breach of
contract. And if that wasn't bad enough,
when actually looking at the historical
changes to the contracts, there used to
be a clause that says that you will be
able to play the game even if you don't
agree to the new changes. All of which
were of course sneakily removed during
the migration.
>> I would say that this uh forceful way of
um migrating the customers is not a term
that is enforcable by by Microsoft which
in this case would mean that they would
be forced to reinstate the old accounts.
And all of this is essentially what the
class action lawsuit is about.
Minecraft's success is entirely due to
the community making it what it is
through, for example, mods and servers
because the base game in itself isn't
really that interesting. And when the
very things that we depend on to
actually enjoy the game are being
threatened by a company that ignores our
rights like this, we as consumers end up
being affected because Mojang is
restricting the way we're able to play
the game. On top of them literally
taking the game away under threat simply
because they knew that nobody would be
fighting back. But there's a limit to
the amount of [ __ ] that people are
willing to take before taking measures.
And Mojang, you [ __ ] crossed it.
Because we're not begging or asking for
mercy anymore. This is a class action
lawsuit that you cannot ignore. I think
this is an important uh case for this
reason that this is becoming a general
business practice right now and it's not
supposed to be like that when you
dealing with consumers especially
children. We're seeing a lot of
companies coming out with this claim
that you don't get the full terms of
service or for their product when you
buy it. The company you're buying from
refer you to their contractual terms on
the website which can change at any time
basically depriving you all your
consumer rights. And this is not right.
This is something we really need to uh
act upon and make sure that we can
exercise our consumer rights.
>> And our objectives are quite simple.
Revert the account migration, meaning
the reinstatement of all unmigrated
accounts where Mojang in the EU has to
be the owner of all customer data.
Comply with contract and consumer
protection laws. So notify about the
changes, get agreement for the changes
without threatening a consequence for
disagreement, remove uninforceable
clauses, including hidden clauses like
the one that allows gambling. clearly
indicate when changes happen and comply
with the terms of our old contracts.
>> I think these goals are both reasonable
and achievable and saying that is coming
from looking at what this case is all
about which is a big corporation abusing
consumer rights and doing so without
anybody responding to it would be wrong.
>> But as you might have expected the legal
system is kind of complicated because if
we take these two examples even though
the core of the issue is the same our
contracts there's a difference in who
was affected by them. Basically, you
need to have the same kind of damage and
the same kind of circumstances for
everybody that goes into the class
action. So, they would each have a
different way of approaching it legally.
Some being easier to pursue than others.
Which is why the account migration is
such a great option because you paid for
something which they then took from you
under threat. All of which is very
easily quantifiable damages which
basically affected everyone before 2023
including those who did migrate because
it was done under threat. And since the
account migration is tied to our
contracts just like everything else, we
can then use it to resolve most issues
with a single process.
>> We need to decide on how we formulate
this claim. What is the damage that's
been done? And how are we going to prove
that? And uh actually the evidence is
going to decide for us how we're going
to do this. And that is the reason for
this video because we are now at the
stage where we need you, the Minecraft
player, to say that you want to
participate in the class action lawsuit
and to tell us how you were affected so
that we can then identify and form the
group that will participate. And the
more submissions we get, the more likely
we are to achieve what we've set out to
do and show Mojang that they don't get
to do whatever the [ __ ] they want.
>> Obviously, it's always decided on the
evidence and how well we can present
that to a court and make them understand
what's actually at stake here, which is
the consumer's right to actually resist
being abused by a big company.
>> Well, the first thing I want to say is
thank you because it's thanks to those
donations that we now actually have a
chance to fight back in a way that's
never really been done before. And if we
win, Mojang will also have to pay back
our legal costs, which also
unfortunately goes the other way.
Meaning that I would essentially go
bankrupt if we were to lose, which is
always a possibility. But I don't want
to live with the regret of not trying
simply because I was too afraid of
losing. So bring it on, Mojang. I'll see
you in court.
And even though it feels a little bit
wrong to mention it, we are fighting a
billion dollar corporation that can [ __ ]
out money faster than privacy
violations. If you do feel like
supporting what we're doing, the
GoFundMe still exists.