This is Minecraft, the game that screwed its community so hard that we're about to sue them in a class action lawsuit.
You see, in December of 2024, I uploaded this video in which I exposed Mojang
the creators of Minecraft, for breaking consumer protection law and exposing children to gambling.
And while I tried to seek justice for myself
I wasn't able to do so because my government is kind of incompetent
making access to justice basically impossible if you're not rich as fuck.
So I tried adding a GoFundMe campaign at the end to finance a class action lawsuit
because this wasn't something that affected just me.
And obviously, there's no way that would actually work
right?
YouTuber Kiabru- Is suing Mojang.
Illegally changing- They publicly funded- It's already nearly on a million Gs.
19 on trending right now.
It's exceeded it.
Completed its funding.
Already passed- $120,000.
That's a lot.
No way the class- Dude, look at this.
That's gotta be one of the fastest-growing crowdfunding campaigns.
We raised $150,000 within days.
Oh, it's fucking happening.
Where we now have access to legal representation and can proceed with the class action lawsuit.
Yes.
My name is Bjorn Persson.
I'm a member of the Swedish Borrower Association.
I run a law firm together with my colleague
Conny Larsson.
And we're working with this lawsuit since it's part of our practice and are looking to
um, run this, uh, lawsuit as a class action against Mojang because we think it's an important issue that needs to be addressed.
To give you a little recap, Minecraft is one of those games that anyone can modify to add things that it didn't originally have.
And what I wanted to do was add guns to the game to recreate an old game that I used to play as a child that had unfortunately been shut down.
But right as it was about to release
Mojang said that, "A recent directive from Mojang leadership determined that guns and weapons were considered non-compliant features.
" Meaning that they had to be completely removed
implying the shutdown of dozens of projects, including mine.
But when actually looking into it, even though they said that guns and weapons were specifically prohibited by the game's legal agreement
when actually looking for these specific prohibitions, you'd come to find that they didn't actually exist.
So Mojang was making shit up and pretending it was part of the Terms of Service
a type of contract, which as you've guessed
is kind of illegal.
A contract is an agreement between two parties and both parties need to agree what the meaning of the contract is.
You can't be forced into new rules that apply to your contract unless you've been notified
as well as having a choice whether to actually accept those terms or just be able to keep using what you already have.
And since this is a hidden clause where guns are just one of the many examples that exist
Mojang can do whatever they want, like applying a different version of the same clause so you never know which one you're gonna get
changing their minds at any time, like they did with the guns three times
and even go against their own rules, like allowing gambling even though they publicly pretend like it's forbidden.
But obviously, shit gets worse.
Because when a company changes its terms of service
it's required to notify its users about the changes and get their agreement for it.
And out of the 47 times they changed their legal agreements
they never told anyone about it.
We know this because I went through thousands of archived pages for every single legal agreement that the game has ever had to see if a single word had changed.
And Mojang not notifying anyone of changes makes perfect sense
since in their own words, "It is up to you to check back to see if these guidelines have changed
" so that it's not their responsibility to tell you.
There's a lot of things that you really can't do with the contract and have it enforceable against the consumers.
You have this legislation under European consumer law that
uh, mandates that the company that changes
uh, the terms need to inform the consumers about this.
And they can't enforce the, the new changes without giving
uh, the consumers a choice.
And if not telling anyone wasn't already bad enough- They removed the notice when the software terms were updated.
This is obviously making it harder for the consumers to exercise their rights.
Because not only is it our responsibility to check when changes happen
but they also make it borderline impossible to tell when they actually did.
Which is quite ironic coming from the company that says
"We are trying to be open, honest
and most importantly, trusting.
" But of course, it only gets worse.
Remember how the original email from Mojang said that guns were specifically prohibited by these three legal agreements where one of them didn't even exist?
This is something I even pointed out in the last video.
By the Mojang brand guidelines, guidelines that literally do not exist.
Well, it turns out that they do exist as its own hidden internal document under a strict NDA that does contain the prohibitions for guns.
The very same document where Mojang internally recognizes loot boxes as gambling.
And what pisses me off even more than them trying to apply a contract that was literally impossible to access without whistleblowers was that while they left us on hold for six months because their CEO was on vacation
they officially partnered with Nerf, the gun company
even though these guidelines say that gun-like toys are forbidden.
Fucking hypocrites.
But as you probably guessed it, it only gets worse.
You see, when buying Minecraft, you create a Mojang account that is then used to play the game.
At least, that's how it used to be.
Because Mojang was bought by Microsoft in 2014
where just a few years later, Mojang would announce that
"We've decided that moving forward, all of our games will require a Microsoft account to play.
And if you didn't want to migrate your account
you won't be able to log in anymore
which means you won't be able to play either.
" In other words, either migrate your account and give Microsoft all of your data
or they take away what you paid for.
And this is what you call a threat.
But not only did they threaten everyone, they also sneakily modified their terms of service to give themselves permission to cancel your account if they simply felt like it.
And you see, when purchasing a game like Minecraft
that essentially means that you purchased a license to download and play the game where the conditions of that license are within the terms of service.
This is important because if a company wanted to change the way a service works
by, for example, changing their terms of service
that new version would only apply to the new users or the ones that explicitly agreed to the changes.
In simple terms, if the contract used to say that you will be able to play the game
if the company doesn't like that anymore, they can't take it away from you because that would be called breach of contract
which is kind of illegal.
And what happened here was that Mojang was forcing everyone to migrate
saying things like, "You will not be able to access the game.
Migration is mandatory.
Won't be able to play Minecraft.
Must be migrated to a Microsoft.
" Players need to move to a Microsoft account.
Mojang accounts to Microsoft accounts.
Where funnily enough, they had the balls to say that this was voluntary three times.
So voluntary, in fact, that if you didn't do it
they took away what you paid for.
This was a forced migration, where we obviously didn't have much of a choice.
The only choice you had was to terminate your account.
And not only were they forcing everyone to give-.
..
their data to a company with a world record of privacy violations
which got recently fined $20 million by the FTC for illegally collecting information on children
most Minecraft players are children.
But in doing so, they also forced you to agree to Microsoft and Xbox's legal agreements
all under the threat of them taking away what you paid for if you didn't do what they wanted.
A contract needs to, uh, be entered into freely
and that obviously means that you need to have a
a choice between agreeing or not agreeing.
Just presenting one choice is not really, uh
an agreement.
But even though it was illegal, Mojang still went ahead with it
which resulted in millions of people losing access to what they paid for
some of which were never even notified that it was happening to begin with
only finding out years later that their purchase had been nullified.
But when actually contacting Mojang to complain, you'd come to find that they wouldn't answer questions
and automatically close most tickets asking for answers.
And when asking Microsoft about it, they would say that.
..
"I've discussed your issue with Mojang support and came to the conclusion that the migration is within the Minecraft Terms and Conditions.
" In other words, "We've investigated ourselves and found nothing wrong.
" But unfortunately for them, this user knows his rights.
And when asking Microsoft to cite his contract for where it says that a Microsoft account is required to play
Microsoft said, "End User License Agreements are constantly updated.
Please refer to the current one," where the current one says
"If you originally signed up through a Mojang account
you must migrate to a Microsoft account in order to keep using the services.
" But this wasn't part of the contract when the user had bought the game
to which Microsoft replied, "I understand that this is your interpretation
but this EULA applies for any user regardless of the date of creation
" further stating that, "Your contract is the new EULA.
The old one doesn't apply anymore.
You agreed to these Terms by using the service.
" Where they then immediately closed the ticket
refusing to answer any further questions.
And this is a perfect example of fucking up in writing
because it confirms the idea that.
..
It is up to you to check back to see if these guidelines have changed.
And that they don't care about agreement, since they claim that you agreed to changes that they didn't even tell you about.
So Mojang voided everyone's contract since they say that they don't apply anymore.
And you fucking guessed it, this is breach of contract.
And if that wasn't bad enough, when actually looking at the historical changes to the contracts
there used to be a clause that says that you will be able to play the game even if you don't agree to the new changes
all of which were, of course, sneakily removed during the migration.
I would say that this, uh, forceful way of
um, migrating the customers is not a term that is enforceable by Microsoft
which in this case would mean that they would be forced to reinstate the old accounts.
And all of this is essentially what the class action lawsuit is about.
Minecraft's success is entirely due to the community making it what it is
through, for example, mods and servers, because the base game in itself isn't really that interesting.
And when the very things that we depend on to actually enjoy the game are being threatened by a company that ignores our rights like this
we as consumers end up being affected because Mojang is restricting the way we're able to play the game.
On top of them literally taking the game away under threat simply because they knew that nobody would be fighting back.
But there's a limit to the amount of shit that people are willing to take before taking measures.
And Mojang?
You fucking crossed it, because we're not begging or asking for mercy anymore.
This is a class action lawsuit that you cannot ignore.
I think this is an important, uh
case for this reason that this is becoming a general business practice right now
and it's not supposed to be like that when you're dealing with consumers
especially children.
We are seeing a lot of companies coming out with this claim that you don't get the full terms of service or for their product when you buy it.
The company you're buying from refer you to their
uh, contractual terms on the website, which can change at any time
basically depriving you all your consumer rights.
And this is not right.
This is something really needed to, uh
act upon and make sure that we can exer- exercise our consumer rights.
And our objectives are quite simple.
Revert the account migration, meaning the reinstatement of all unmigrated accounts where Mojang in the EU has to be the owner of all customer data
comply with contract and consumer protection laws, so notify about the changes
get agreement for the changes without threatening a consequence for disagreement
remove unenforceable clauses, including hidden clauses like the one that allows gambling
clearly indicate when changes happen, and comply with the terms of our old contracts.
I think these goals are re- both reasonable and achievable
and saying that is coming from looking at what this case is all about
which is, uh, a big corporation abusing consumer rights and doing so without anybody responding to it would be wrong.
But as you might have expected, the legal system is kind of complicated
because if we take these two examples, even though the core of the issue is the same
our contracts, there's a difference in who was affected by them.
Basically, you need to have the same kind of damage and the same kind of circumstances for everybody that
uh, goes into the class action.
So they would each have a different way of approaching it legally
some being easier to pursue than others, which is why the account migration is such a great option
because you paid for something which they then took from you under threat
all of which is very easily quantifiable damages
which basically affected everyone before 2023, including those who did migrate because it was done under threat.
And since the account migration is tied to our contracts
just like everything else, we can then use it to resolve most issues with a single process.
We need to decide on how we formulate this claim.
What is the damage that's been done and how are we going to prove that?
And, uh, actually the evidence is gonna decide for us how we're gonna do this.
And that is the reason for this video
because we are now at the stage where we need you
the Minecraft player, to say that you want to participate in the class action lawsuit
and to tell us how you were affected so that we can then identify and form the group that will participate.
And the more submissions we get, the more likely we are to achieve what we've set out to do and show Mojang that they don't get to do whatever the fuck they want.
Obviously, it's always decided on the evidence and how well we can present that to a court and make them understand what's actually at stake here
which is the consumer's, uh, right to actually resist being abused by a big company.
Where the first thing I want to say is thank you
because it's thanks to those donations that we now actually have a chance to fight back in a way that's never really been done before
and if we win, Mojang will also have to pay back our legal costs
which also unfortunately goes the other way, meaning that I would essentially go bankrupt if we were to lose
which is always a possibility.
But I don't want to live with the regret of not trying simply because I was too afraid of losing.
So bring it on, Mojang.
I'll see you in court.
And even though it feels a little bit wrong to mention it
we are fighting a billion-dollar corporation that can shit out money faster than privacy violations.
If you do feel like supporting what we're doing
the GoFundMe still exists.