Back in 2015, Apple introduced the 12-inch
MacBook.
The first model ever to feature an Apple logo
that didn’t light up.
And since then, the MacBook Pro and MacBook
Air have also received the same treatment.
This caused some controversy, since the glowing
Apple logo has been around for over two decades
and has become an iconic design element of
Apple’s notebooks.
So why was the illuminated Apple logo removed?
Well, that’s exactly what I’ll explain
right now.
So when the 12-inch MacBook was introduced,
it was the thinnest model in Apple’s history.
In fact, at 13.1 millimeters, it was 24% thinner
than the MacBook Air.
But that dramatic improvement didn’t come
without compromises.
For example, Apple had to create a new super-thin
keyboard that featured butterfly mechanisms
instead of the traditional scissor design.
They claimed the new keyboard was an improvement,
but that didn’t turn out to be the case.
It was extremely faulty and resulted in a
class action lawsuit, with Apple eventually
reverting back to the scissor keyboards.
But another compromise of the 12-inch MacBook
was the non-illuminated Apple logo.
Since the display was so thin, two problems
arose.
First, if there was a strong light source
behind the display, you could actually see
a subtle hotspot in the center of the screen.
Since the glowing Apple logo was a transparent
cutout that allowed the display’s backlight
to shine through, but also allowed external
light to enter.
This meant using the MacBook outside could
cause color inaccuracies on the display.
So to eliminate this potential issue, Apple
had to seal off the display’s chassis entirely,
which meant getting rid of the translucent
logo.
But there was another benefit to this approach,
the thinness of the MacBook’s display combined
with the Apple logo cutout, caused structural
rigidity issues.
Just like the iPad Pro was easily bent thanks
to the Apple Pencil attachment cutout, the
MacBook could’ve easily been bent due to
the Apple logo cutout.
So replacing its weak spot with a piece of
metal, helped eliminate this structural weakness.
The third reason why Apple got rid of their
glowing logo is for purely aesthetic reasons.
Back when the trend started in 1999 with the
PowerBook G3, Apple was mounting a comeback.
Steve Jobs had just returned to the company
three years prior, and he put a huge focus
on establishing a new reputation for Apple.
Since they’d fallen out of favor with customers
over the past decade.
That’s what sparked the Think Different
ad campaign, and radical new computer designs
like the iMac and PowerBook.
It was the first time a glowing Apple logo
had been used, and it was crucial in creating
brand awareness.
Seeing a prominently displayed Apple logo
in public reminded people that the company
was still around, and was actually creating
some really cool products.
But today, Apple has been moving away from
this overt brand strategy and shifting to
something more subtle.
For example, they could’ve put an Apple
logo on the AirPods Max, like almost every
other headphone manufacturer, but they didn’t.
Also, with the 24-inch iMac, Apple removed
their logo from the product’s chin for the
first time since 2004.
And it makes sense why they don’t need their
logo to be as overtly display anymore.
Apple isn’t struggling to garner attention
or win customers from other brands.
They’re by far the biggest and most recognizable
tech company in the world.
With almost every product they create dominating
their respective market.
Apple has also been unifying their product
design in recent years.
And since the iPad, iPhone, and Mac desktops
all have non-illuminated Apple logos, it makes
sense to carry that design language through
to the MacBook line.
So while it’s understandable to feel sentimental
about losing the glowing Apple logo, it can
also spark some excitement.
Since it represents a new era of Apple, with
plenty of incredible products yet to come.
This is Greg from Apple Explained, thanks
for watching till the end, and I’ll see
you in the next video.