your boy's ready what are the LG drops
it
[Laughter]
four m.2 pcie Jen at least four parts on
this thing we're going with the 12 900k
because the
don't worry I caught it with the foot
because the chaos
the chaos wasn't out yet how do you like
the case it's awesome I know right
do you know how to hold a steam bag
okay this is Jake's phone actually so
I'm not going to check his text but
maybe maybe Jake Hey Jake are you an
earshot or like I can text him whoa
Colin tell me a little story
all right all right that's enough of
that story this was actually last week
but we missed it and that was not
intense
that's not a word that wasn't
intentional either it's not a word
low-key hock my phone at my laptop
and that was not intention
so when they saw a gigabyte release look
look at him he's all sweaty he's all
stressed out I am the opposite of stress
right now
just put it down it was a very short
distance drop
I'm trying to put it down
God damn it We don't even know how much
this costs it's probably like 70 grand
?
oh there goes my lunch how about now
it's a little heavy, a little clumsy you
might say okay but
this is the moment where you are second
most likely to bung up your computer
okay see these little standoffs in here
let's show let's show all the
you did a great job of applying those
stickers but they made it a little heavy
they're a little front heavy now so they
fell right
oh ho ho ho ho ho oh ho ho ho ho ho
my goodness
you gotta do something
a little special I don't think I'm gonna
let you pick this one up
ready one two three I can't believe
you've done this
oh God oh God
NVMe like you see here these are
gonna be spicy and then around back
so that's where a ton of our air intake
is going to come from but just that not
gonna be enough for the there goes my
back panel I appear to have experienced
some shipping damage three two I'm
holding the heavy side yeah don't drop
it okay I didn't drop it ow you just put
all the weight it was on your foot cool
well that's all the hard work yes you
should okay so we're gonna do a four
node actually wait what oh my oh my God
oh my God how do you do that you just
literally
holy
are you
kidding me dude what's the actual is
wrong with you
oh my god oh oh I want to throw up I
really
oh
do you think it still works no
did you hear the noise in me well it's a
pretty
night still at work
okay lunch says it still works I think
that drive will die faster than the
other ones okay that's nice but that
wasn't the bet
I'll buy you lunch whatever yes
and safely and
we are off to a really really good start
here as an Infamous Butterfingers I have
dropped my fair share of phones I
present exhibit a my iPhone 6 that
regrettably succumbed to that most cruel
of Mistresses gravity on both front and
back has an included screen protector
and that did come in handy I actually
dropped it on the pavement
like an hour before we filmed this it
was in pristine condition
but it handled it like a champ all it
did was Dent the aluminum frame a little
bit I've certainly had worse
watching the stupid way that I'm gonna
do things he's like no no really There's
A Better Way Linus it's like dude I know
but I'm gonna do it this way anyway see
watch
there we go see it worked
no I'm not taking it out I just want to
whoops today we're gonna build an entire
budget gaming PC higher budget higher
budget higher budget game careful don't
scratch it buddy here I'm not scratching
them Kyle geez man relax Kyle people are
gonna get that use the freaking guy oh
my God what are you doing come on man
I'm falling behind so
oh
oh you're through hello
how you doing buddy hey
here's some sawdust ah I could maybe
just go like right here whoa Linus is
the reason I have trust issues which I
guess isn't the end of the world because
the monitors are nope 12th gen
soon on fans fun fact in computer terms
90 and
you can put a GPU in here though look
GPU power if you wanted like an a100 or
something again if you had a very
purpose build specific use case oh my
god oh geez is it okay crap I bent a lot
of pins lioness
that's really bad I can fix it oh my
gosh you're crushing things and people
always thought
that wasn't my fault
the Shelf just fell down
they're not attached to anything they're
just okay just just stop well what are
we supposed to do with these pickles now
I have my feet in the rice
there's notes in the script well I'm not
clearly not looking at them oh my God
okay well that was supposed to land in
here
I'm trying to trying to build a computer
here jeez
oh geez especially for a webcam right so
it seems like a pretty good
where'd it go
ah binus is looking angrier than he was
before
trying to feel out his opponent oh
get some energy
there you go
hmm
[Applause]
fantastic 20 minutes not too bad
20 minutes what a blue screened shut up
I didn't do anything
no I don't have an aura
what the was that that's the center
piece of the screen okay it's only a
little bent of both our PC and our
Monitor and
what you'll be accustomed to if you use
whoa hi
so it's almost impossible to get
everything you know matching under
all conditions well I guess we
inadvertently are going to check and see
oh yeah how durable it is if you happen
to drop your PlayStation or something
I've actually done this before so don't
freak out
it's a werewolf Thing Once I bite them
they start dropping things
okay
ah sorry I have a sort of a measuring
tape cool whoa whoa
what just happened
oh I'm glad it wasn't me
oh oh this was a bad idea oh I got hit
by heart yeah you did you did I would
appreciate it if those hadn't fallen off
the table if it helps at all they were
Christians by my butt had you considered
that or no okay I mean
someone whoa Linus someone probably
considered that dude
solid state it's probably fine did you
scratch the motherboard you know what
the peel was still here
yeah whoa hey what did you line as I
turn around for two seconds and you're
dropping things well no it's just that
the
it cut me off he cut me off I think the
test reporter thing slipped yeah yeah
between my hands excuses
yeah so four this makes recording easy
but what we found is that these custom
carabiner
request to some Pastor resolution
there you go yeah uniform brightness
mode is actually on wow so then we're
good well that's fantastic
yes
thank you for watching