in this video i'll teach you the core of
the kotlin programming language
kotlin is a general purpose statically
typed language that has become extremely
popular in the last few years
kotlin can be used on both the client
and the server which means the code can
be run either on the user's device
the client or on some computer in the
cloud called the server
which responds to requests from the
client
on the client kotlin is now widely used
for android development
to write apps for the 2.5 billion
devices running the android operating
system
kotlin has seen a huge rise in
popularity
and i can promise you it will only
become more popular in the years to come
kotlin is an example of a programming
language which is a way for me and you
to communicate with computers
at the end of the day computers only
understand binary zeros and ones
so over the years we've created many
different ways to instruct the computer
what we'd like it to do each of these
approaches is called a programming
language
and you've probably heard of some of
them such as c or java or javascript
since kotlin was created much more
recently it has taken the lessons from
the earlier languages
to make something that is both powerful
and easy to use
java and kotlin have a special
relationship since they're compatible
with each other
kotlin is what java would look like if
it was designed today
to write kotlin code i'm going to be
using a program called intellij which
you can download for free from the
internet
to start out with i created an empty
file called kotlin minutes
the file extension for kotlin files is
dot kt and the code we write will be
inside this
special function called main we'll talk
more about functions later
in classic fashion the first thing we'll
do is print out hello world
so we'll use this function called
println and type in hello world in
double quotes
now we'll execute our code by hitting
this green arrow which will compile and
run our code
compiling just means taking the symbols
and keyboards you write and turning that
into something that the computer can
actually execute
you can see the output in this run tool
window that pops up where it says hello
world as we expect
let's start our tour of kotlin with
variables a variable is a piece of data
which has a name
and a type for example strings are a
sequence of characters
so my first name would be stored as a as
a string type
the way we'll declare the variable is
with a special keyword called val
you can tell it's a keyword since it'll
turn a different color in the editor
in kotlin every variable must have a
type that's why we say
kotlin is statically typed so in this
example the name of the variable is
first name and the type is string
because we're setting the value of the
variable equal to drawhold right away
we actually don't need to specify that
this is of type string
this is a nice feature of kotlin called
type inference where
if it's obvious what the type is we
don't need to explicitly
indicate it there's also an important
concept of whether a variable is
read-only or
readable and writable if the value of a
variable can change
after it's initialized then we have to
declare it with this var
keyword since my weight goes up every
holiday season because of how many
cookies i'm eating
we'll use var for that but my first name
will never change
so that'll be a vowel there are a few
other built-in types in kotlin in
addition to string and integer which we
just saw
for example double is for decimals like
2.5
and booleans only have two values either
true
or false as you write more code it's
sometimes helpful to leave yourself a
note about why you wrote the code in a
certain way
these are called comments and you can
leave a comment by using a double slash
commented lines are ignored by the
computer now that we've talked about
variables
let's look at operators which allow us
to manipulate these variables
for example we can combine two strings
into a longer string with a plus sign
which is called concatenation here we're
printing out the value of s1 plus
s2 in this variable called combined so
when we run the program we get the
result of call me maybe which is a
concatenation of call me
and maybe this is an example of a binary
operator because it takes in two inputs
there are several different binary
operators for numbers as you might
expect
with two integers here having value nine
and four we can add them together and
get thirteen
we can also subtract them multiply them
divide them or find the remainder after
the division with this percent sign
that would be 1 in this case let's talk
a bit more about strings
strings are a sequence of characters and
there are a bunch of useful things you
can do with them for example
retrieving a character in the series by
indexing into the string
like this in kotlin like most other
programming languages we start counting
at zero so the first character k
will be at position zero and the second
character o will be position one in the
output we can see the first two
letters of kotlin we can also check if a
string is empty using the method is
empty which returns a boolean true or
false value
or we can get the length of a string
which is an integer by using the dot
length property
if we run this we can see that my string
kotlin is not empty because it has
characters
and there are six characters which is
why the length is six
another method is substring which will
extract a portion of the string between
the start and end index that we provide
so substring with parameters 2 and 4
will output tl because we will start at
t
which is index 2 include index 3 the l
and then go up 2 but not include index 4
the i
one really handy tip as you start
writing more kotlin is to explore
other methods available to you by
hitting the dot or period
after writing the name of your variable
you'll get an auto complete dialog
which shows you all the possible things
you can do with this
variable the period is probably one of
the most important symbols in kotlin
since it allows us to use the built-in
functionality of the language
one thing worth pointing out is that the
options and methods that you get
will depend on the type of the variable
for example the options here
with the integer will be different than
what we had with the string
one last point on the topic of strings
we'll frequently want to print out the
value of a variable
inside a string for that we'll use the
dollar sign to do string interpolation
the dollar sign means that we'll replace
the variable here
with the contents of it inside the
string so if we run this we can see the
output is the string is kotlin because
the value of my string
is kotlin we can use interpolation for
variables of any type
let's move on to conditionals which are
a way to execute certain code depending
on a condition
an if statement is an example of flow
control which will evaluate whether
a statement is true or false and execute
some code only if it's true
for example we can print out a message
if this
exam score variable is greater than 70.
because the value 88 is larger than 70
when we run the code we see you passed
because we're running the code inside
the if block
the statement we're evaluating here can
be anything with a true or false return
value
so for example we could do exams greater
than 70
greater than or equal to less than less
than or equal to
equal to or not equal to a value
i'll change this back to exam score
greater than 70 but what if you want to
do something if that condition fails
for that we'll use an else block and the
code inside of here will get run if the
condition fails
in this case that means that the exam
score is less than 70 so we'll print out
you failed
and now let's change the exam score to
55 which is something that will trigger
the else block to run and so here in the
output you can see the message
you failed we often want to hold a bunch
of variables at once
instead of defining them one at a time
for that we can use collections
for example instead of having a separate
variable here
for each of my friends names we can have
one variable which is a list of strings
containing all my friends names
so now if i wanted to print out the
third element in this list we could do
that
by looking at index 2 of our names list
remember that kotlin is 0 indexed so ali
is at index 0
maya index 1 and chan at index 2. when
we run this
we do indeed see 10 in the output by
default
collections in kotlin are immutable
which means we can't add or remove
elements from the list
if we want to change the contents we
must declare the list as a mutable list
by changing the declaration now we are
able to add a fourth element
all elements in a collection must have
the same type so in this example
everything is of type string
and we could actually make that explicit
by adding this string type parameter
to the declaration if we tried adding
something else into the list we would
get a compile error for example
here we're trying to add 80 which is an
integer into the list
and if i hover over it says the integer
literal does not conform to the expected
type
string it's really common to do
something on every element
in a collection the most common way of
doing that is with a for loop
for example if we wanted to print out
each element in our list of friends
names
we'd write the for loop like this for
name in names
println name if we run this we can see
the output is the three names in the
list the way i think about this
is that in every cycle or iteration of
the for loop
the variable name will take on one
element of the list
it'll go in order so first it'll be ali
then maya and then chan
the other common use of for loops is to
do something a certain number of times
we can use for i in 1.5 to execute
something
exactly five times so if you run this we
can see that the operation that we're
doing five times
is println and we're printing out i each
time
where i will take on each of the values
1 through 5 before it exits the for loop
if we don't want to include the last
number then we can do for i in 1 until 5
and that will just print out the numbers
1 through 4.
next we'll talk about functions
functions are a way to combine chunks of
your code so we can reuse them
throughout our program
this makes our code easier to read and
think about we can create a function
with the fun keyword followed by the
function name
so in this example it's my function
followed by open and close parentheses
and then the body of the function goes
inside of these curly braces
now we can invoke our function from the
main function just by
calling it with the open and closed
parenthesis if we run this the body of
my function gets
executed so we print out hello if we
want to give this function some input we
can add the parameter name and type to
the function signature
so here we have a parameter name of name
and the type of string
in the body of the function we can treat
the parameter as a normal variable
so here we're including that input into
the print line
you'll notice back in the main function
that we now have an error when trying to
call
my function and that's because whoever
invokes this function
is responsible for passing in the
correct number and type
of parameters let's pass in the string j
for the parameter and if we run this now
we can see
hello j as the output we can also set
the visibility of functions to be
private so they can't be accessed from
other classes or files
people always ask me what kind of
private fun are you having
but that's the topic for another video
finally the concept of null is really
important in kotlin
null means having no value and if a
variable is allowed to have no value
then we need to update the type to
include a question mark
this means that the variable instagram
bio is a nullable string
so on instagram if you've written a bio
then this variable would have a string
value
but if it's not set it would be null the
important thing to remember
is that we can't call any methods on
something which is null
one way to get around this is to check
if the variable is not null
and then in the body of this if
statement we can now safely call any
method we want
in this case because we're setting
instagram bio to null
we'll fail the check on line 3 which
means when we run the program we get an
empty output
however if we update instagram bio to be
a string then we will get into the body
of the
if statement and that's how we're
printing out uppercase growth
the other way of doing this is to use a
shorthand for exactly this if
check which is the question mark dot
operator so we can say instagram bio
question mark dot to upper case and this
means we'll only call this method
on this variable or this object if it's
non-null
so if we print this out we can see that
we now get growth in uppercase
printed out twice that's pretty much the
core of kotlin
we went over variables operators strings
if statements for loops and functions
if you're interested in learning more
about all the good stuff in kotlin
i'd love if you hit the subscribe button
and like this video thanks for watching
and i'll see you in the next one