[Drums]
I don't want you to know how I'm feeling
but you can read me like an open book
Don't put on a show, I'm alright here
You don't need to cry
Or show me sympathy
Don't waste your time on me
I'm used to being alone
So step away from me
I don't need anything apart from distance
to make sure that you're safe
'Cause I'm a ticking time bomb in need of assistance
but I need to know that you're okay
So hurry on by
I'll see you off with a smile
I'm used to being alone
So I guess this is goodbye
Just get rid of me, my toxicity
will cut you like a knife
Like the river flows, just head off and go,
leave the biggest weights behind
Leave the burden in your life
and move on
So hurry on by
I'll see you off with a smile
I'm used to being alone
So I guess this is goodbye
Da Da Da Da Da Da Da
Da Da Da Da
Da Da Da Da Da Da Da Da Da
Da Da Da Da Da Da Da
Da Da Dai
Da Da Da Da Da Dai
Dai-a Da Da Da Da Da Dai
Da Da Da Da Da Da
Da Da Dai Duai Da Da Dai