oh
ah so back in my day leh, every Tuesday
pack of wolves waiting for us. one of
them was named Bob. Bob was the fastest
and one time Bob caught one of our
friends
we had to let them go. That's why I do
karate (?)
I learned that from my online karate
class, first week, gold belt, I know it
wasn't even invented yet power leh, don't
matter when you have technique
back in my day leh, when I went to school I had to walk 20
miles, uphill, both ways, in a blizzard(?)
carrying a bag of rocks. -Why? you're from Shenzhen.
Shenzhen
we also got chased by lions. back in my
day leh, didn't have Internet, so if you
wanted to learn physics you had to find
Newton
and ask him yourself also let in my day
chemistry so much simpler Elemental chart
have four elements water Earth Fire and
Air all was in harmony until the Fire
Nation attacked
okay okay that's not the wolf. math not
the same as before! see kids nowaday will
never know the struggle of Timmy having
to buy 52 watermelons. Susan on a train
traveling north(?) at 50 mile a(n) hour
calculate the mass of the Sun. If Ray
make 280,000$ a year why he's still
single? if a squid plus b squared equal
minus B plus or minus square root of LOL
@gmail.com /(forward slash) Smack That
subscribe button, what time is it? English
today too easy back in my day I had to
write on a typewriter with half the
letters missing try write a essay
without "a". Nowadays your kids have it so
easy leh, you watch YouTube video on your
iPad, Chinese kids made your iPad, and the
video ages ago leh, we had this thing
called the pencil, the tip always broke
'cause we were too cheap to afford to
go on. pencil with fidget Spinners that
took skill I had this trick where I spin
it across my thumb but most of the time
it will fly across the room with the
pencil let count the rubber American
called this eraser okay, had a very
important function
to be stabbed by the pencil. Nowadays with
these kids all you have to do go on your
laptop, go on Zoom, you can pass without
even wearing pants
kids nowadays. all I remember we used to
get the tension for drawing Essence on
our books what's the tension the
tensions when you get sent to the gulag
the tensionless when you get sent to the
shadow realm the tensions the place
where you wait two hours check the clock
five minutes pass oh yeah that they
canceled out of school because Justin
identifies as a pigeon and got offended
hello everybody Stephen can't land
acting job so he made his own show called GINORMO!
but we have some cool limited edition
stuff like this superhero costume you one
by Stephen Genie and Nathan in the show
that's not the real costume it's just a
another version, 'cause the real one too
expensive we can't afford it. And there's
limited edition metallic foil poster
featuring the cast of the show thank you
very much for supporting ginormous we
already have fantastic reviews like
Disney minus what the hell I just
watched "if Power Rangers ran out of
budget" if you still haven't seen GINORMO
GINORMO right over here six episodes
weekly quickly so Stephen can stop being
a failure I'll give you a bonus discount
for the heavily discounted price of free
right here
[laughs]
please go