"GUILTY!!" You broke the "Anti-Phone-Zombies Act".
You should not lightly cross the line.
I sentence you for transformation into a turtle and for exile.
("JUSTICE BEAM")
The only condition you could come back is to "learn".
All Phone Zombies Lead to Rome / manbo-p
MUSIC: Yoh Takahashi   ILLUSTRATION: Tsukasa Ryugu
When I was sobbing on an unknown beach,
a king secured me for peace.
However, he was taken everything by his people and he was exiled from the land.
I was in ancient Rome, the beginning of the Roman Republic.
However, in fact, aristocrats(the senate) dominated the power.
Commoners were regarded less than old grasshoppers.
Aristocrats gave delicious foods while commoners fed only mud.
Including disparity in the society, they continued extending the war.
During the war, farms were worn-out and proletarians were increased.
On the other hand, wealth people earned more by using slaves.
Aristocrats even fed me money itself.
Commoners tried to hunt me to cook sashimi.
"Sulla: the Optimates" VS "Marius: the Populares"
"The War of Spartacus". We're entering civil wars.
I was sent to the war zone for being a shell-shield.
"Don't make me a true zombie!! Don't kill Me!"
Caesar, Pompeius, and Crassus!
Populares were ruling Rome and the 1st Triumviratus began.
Now get relieved? Remember guys,
this is the (inevitable) consequence of Phone-Zombies.
Crassus's gone like easy money.
Pompeius went over to the senate. WHY.
(Pompeius:"He’s so cocky." Senators:"Yeah, I know" )
Caesar punished him, but he was assassinated by Brute.
("Et tu, Brute?")
The scar on my shell(Drooling Donkey) would never heal.
Antonius, Lepidus, and Octavianus.
The 2nd Triumviratus began, damply.
Lepidus's gone like easy money.
The new conflict began among those two left.
Am I watching a recording?
Octavianus(adopted child of Caesar) followed his father's footsteps.
Antonius, teamed up with Cleopatra, stood against him.
In the Battle of Actium,
I worked for Octavianus and brought him victory.
He started Principate,
which well-balanced with the power of the senate.
It was totally different from what happened in Caesar's.
("Imperator Caesar Divi Filius Augustus", "Puddingceps", "Pater Patriae")
I've witnessed how people progressed
by "learning" from the past.
Although being a turtle is fine, it's a really peaceful life
Thanks to the Five Good Emperors, it was Pax Romana.
("Nerva","Trajan","Hadrian,"Antoninus Pius","Marcus Aurelius")
With water supply and public baths, it's very comfortable
Maybe I could have been born as a turtle
However, Rome became too large.
Caracalla expanded citizenship in provinces,
which led to the flood of Barracks emperors.
人は争いを繰り返す
"Conflicts between people are repeated.
(Diocletian, Constantine, Theodosius)"
Diocletian advertises himself as God.
("Diocletianus", "I am THE GOD")
Constantinus approved Christianity.
("Remember. Athanasius is the Orthodox Church"
0:03:33.760,0:03:37.540
They aimed unification in their ways,
but only ended up triggering another fight.
デオトシウスは死の淵で苦しみを打ち明けた
Theodosius confessed his suffering at his last moment.
"We were looking for a way to bring peace to everyone.
We were looking for a way to let people help each other.
Now, we ARE still do it.
We human do not have a shell
so we need somebody to leave our back."
"I hope we'll find the way after me"
The wish was never come true.
The Roman Empire fell. Divided by East and West.
I finally understood.
The world is build on people in the past,
who fought each other, acknowledged each other,
and failed again and again.
And I understood we're still halfway.
I, who "learned" it, came back to where I was.
The world looks slightly different.
I know because I've changed.