what did you learn in school did I dare
little boy of mine what did you learn in
school today dear little boy of mine
I learned that Washington never told a
lie I learned that soldiers seldom Dial
earned that everybody's free that's what
the teacher said to me that's what I
learned in school today
that's what I learned in school what did
you learn in school today dear what did
you learn in school day dear little boy
I learned that policemen are my friends
I learned that justice never ends I
learned that murderers die for the
crimes even if we make a mistake
sometime that's what I learned in school
today that's what I learned in school
what did you learn in school did I hear
oh my what did you learn in school today
dear of all of my I learned our
government must be strong it's always
right and never wrong our leaders are
the finest men and we elect them again
and again next element in school
what did you learn in school today
that boy had minor what did you learn in
school today dear
I learned that war is not so bad I
learned about the great ones we have had
before in Germany and in France and
someday I might get my chance and that's
what I learned in school at school
Oh