hello I am a professional Asian that
specializing in Failure management as
parents we need to share our wisdom with
our children use our experiences and
knowledge to guide our children when
they need help this lesson is called
repeat the same thing louder dad I don't
know how to do this question okay let me
see what's going on x equal integral of
e squared okay what's integral of e
squared
I don't know what's the integral I don't
know what's the integral I don't know
what's the I don't know what is the
integral no you answer me the louder you
repeat the more knowledge you're passing
down to your children
what's an integral Rockstar in
my mother
you continue doing this to your children
about to pass out
for maximum effect turn the whole thing
around and make it look like he's
overreacting okay breathe breathe listen
what the hell you're so dramatic what's
the big deal just a math question you
don't know you ask teacher tomorrow no
problem not stop crying you get
constipated next we have a ancient art
this one hits close to home I remember
when I was 10 my mother were randomly
360 no scope me across the kitchen this
is the ancient art of throwing
literally anything
[Music]
I didn't know you were coordinated you
could play baseball
[Laughter]
foreign
[Music]