Hello
I am a professional Asian dad
Specializing in failure management
As parents we need to share our wisdom with our children
Use our experiences and knowledge to guide our children when they need help
This lesson is called repeat the same thing louder
Dad I don't know how to do this question
Okay let me see what's going on
x equal integral of e squared
Okay what's integral of e squared?
[Dazed]
Uh - I don't - I don't know
No no no no no no
What's integral of e squared?
I'd - I don't - I don't know
What's the integral?
I don't know
What's the integral??
I - I don't know
What is the integral???
I don't know what is the integral
No you answer me
The louder you repeat
The more knowledge you're passing down to your children
What's the integral???!
What's an integral???
What's the integral???!?
What's the integral
(Of e squared???!??) Jesus help your boy out
[Guitar Play & Sing] What's the integral of you dumb motherf-
[Breathing Room]
You continue doing this till your children about to pass out
[Cough]
For maximum effect turn the whole thing around and make it look like he's overreacting
Okay breathe breathe listen
What the hell you're so dramatic
What's the big deal? Just a math question
You don't know you ask teacher tomorrow no problem la
Stop crying you'll get constipated
Next we have a ancient art
This one hits close to home
I remember when I was 10
My mother were randomly 360 no scope me across the kitchen
This is the ancient art of throwing
Literally
Anything
[Music]
[Laugh]
I didn't know you were coordinated
You could play baseball you know
[Laugh]
[Laughter]
That really hurt my nose
Hey mom
(I'm...) Working
[Laugh]
[Music]