I swear I will succeed
me too
[Music]
I swim
five
thank you
no rehearsal in life
foreign
[Music]
buy all the Singapore hotels
he is a shoestration I don't know
therefore the past Christmas I was being
full
by International big life
I just received the buying result
we have laws we are out
[Music]
you had to ask me to spend over one half
a million stars are about your feet
you stupid
is a trip
but I'll still view a fire
with the fat brother
what do this
that's great
you certainly sing Captain enough to be
an excellent secretary for the president
I don't have any secretary experience
but I trust that I am the best person of
this job
good
how are your computer skills pretty good
I'm proficient in word presentation
creating spreadsheet
and setting up database and I have
experience
making web patch very impressive
and how would you
describe yourself
I'm hard working and organized
I work well with others and I believe my
personality and ability to learn fast
we are in heaven me to become a good
secretary
MBA understand
yeah