- Stephen
- Hey dad
- You're nine years old
Time to start thinking about career, okay?
- Ah okay i was thinking --
- You're going to be a doctor
[Awkward smile]
- What? I -- I thought you hated doctors
- What? Why?
- Well every time you get sick,
None of us can convince you to see a doctor
You even said you'd rather swim back to China
- Son why you think I tell you to be doctor?
- To help people?
Wuhehehe
- To help people? Hahahaha
To help people? Hahaha hehehe
I raised a donut
You become doctor to take people's money!
- Not to help people? Then why do I need an A1 in math?
- To count the money le
- Um dad I was actually thinking of becoming a YouTuber
🎶Sad Romance - 韩国群星
- What the hell you say?
What you think you bought Bitcoin? Who the hell gonna pay you
- I have 63,000 subscribers
- What the hell six - sixty three thousand dollars?
- No no not dollars, people
- Who the hell want to watch you?
- Well actually they like you, so if you wanna plug my channel
- Pull the subscribe
[Please]
You know your father the wrists sore
Working too hard
When you get to the 100k
Buy your father the rolex watches
Go for a race
English subtitles made by @Aynxul03 | 由 @Aynxul03 听写、打轴