Stephen
Hey dad
You're - nine years old, time to start thinking
about career, okay?
okay i was thinking
you're going to be a doctor
what i i thought you hated doctors
why
well
every time you get sick
none of us can convince you to see a doctor
you even said you'd rather swim back to china
so why do you think i tell you who we daughter to help
to help people.
help him.
i mean
raise the donor
you become doctor to take people's money to help people
don't worry
do i need a a one and math to count the monday
um dad
i was actually thinking of becoming a youtuber
what the hell you say
what you think you bought bitcoin
who the hell don't pay you
i have sixty three thousand
the hairs at sixty three thousand dollar
no no nut dollars people who the hell want to watch
you actually they like you
so if you want to plug my channel to subscribe
you know
your father the wrist so working too hard when you
get to the hundred k by your father
the rolex watches go for this