Let me tell you this horrible story
About that time I was left by my one and only
I was searching, I was browsing
With no results to show
Our love was broad, but now I'm band
Baby where did you go?
Oh Internet, I need you, miss you
Internet, alone without you
Internet, I just keep on searching, searching
Oh Internet, I need you, miss you
Internet, alone without you
Internet, I just keep on searching
With no results showing
www.please.comhome
We both love lots of cookies
Without you I am alone
How will I still cope?
I need you more than ever
You managed all my money
And we shopped together
Oh Internet, I need you, miss you
Internet, alone without you
Internet, I just keep on searching, searching
Oh Internet, I need you, miss you
Internet, alone without you
Internet, I just keep on searching
With no results showing
Wait a minute, what is this feeling?
No pings, notifications
Or reminders of a world that is not
That great to be in
I feel free
The Internet has ceased
Is that what it takes to find this peace?
Ooh, wait a minute
What is this feeling?
I've missed this feeling
Oh Internet, I thought I'd miss you
Internet, but life without you
Internet, It's almost refreshing, freshing
Oh Internet, I thought I'd miss you
Internet, I'm fine without you
Internet, thanks for all that you've done
But now I must move on
Oh Internet