Feeling out of place in this place right now
Everything has changed for the worse
Somehow everyone's off the face and I'm the odd one out
The DJ isn't great and the music's loud
I would rather be in my bed sleeping
Than deal with all these people
One shot two shot three shot four, all my friends are on the floor
I can't do this anymore
I should have stayed at home these days
Don't feel the shed
Everyone's on coca***
I swear I hate this place
I should have stay
I da da da da da la la la la la
La la la la la la la la
But na na na na na na na da rules
Someone put me out of my misery
Feel like everyone here is judging me
How do you call this fun
Oh
It's a mystery
Call it what you want just stop calling me
I would rather be in my bed sleeping
Than deal with all these people
One shot two shot three shot four
All my friends are on the floor
I can't do this anymore
I should have stayed at home these days
Don't feel the same
Everyone's on coca***
I swear i hate this place
I should i stay and hold
La la
La la la da da da da da da da da da da da da da da
But da da da da da da da da
One shot two shot
Three shot four
All my friends are on the floor
I can't do this anymore
I should have stayed at home these days
Don't feel the
I swear i hate this place
I should have stayed at home
But na na na na na na na na na
Na na na na na
Na na na na na na na na na na na na na na na
But it da da da da na na I should have stayed at home