stephen hey then you're nine years old  time to start thinking about career okay  oh okay i was thinking you're going to  be a doctor  what i i thought you hated doctors what  why well every time you get sick none of  us can convince you to see a doctor you  even said you'd rather swim back to  china so  why you think i tell you to be doctor to  help people  to help people to help  people i raised a donor you become  doctor to take people's money not to  help people then why do i need an a1 in  math to count the money  um dad i was actually thinking of  becoming a youtuber  what the hell are you saying what you  think you bought bitcoin who the hell  gonna pay you  i have 63 000 subscribers what the hell  is it sixty three thousand dollars no no  not dollars people who the hell wrong to  watch you  actually they like you so if you wanna  plug my channel subscribe  you know your father the wrists are  working too hard when you get to the  100k  buy your father the rolex watches go for  risk