- Stephen
- Hey Dad
- You're nine years old
- Time to start thinking about career
- okay
- oh okay i was thinking
- you're going to
- be a doctor
- What I I thought you hated doctors
- What?
- Why?
- Well every time you get sick none of
- us can convince you to see a doctor you
- even said you'd rather swim back to
- china so
why you think i tell you to be doctor to
help people
to help people to help
people i raised a donor you become
doctor to take people's money not to
help people then why do i need an a1 in
math to count the money
um dad i was actually thinking of
becoming a youtuber
what the hell are you saying what you
think you bought bitcoin who the hell
gonna pay you
i have 63 000 subscribers what the hell
is it sixty three thousand dollars no no
not dollars people who the hell wrong to
watch you
actually they like you so if you wanna
plug my channel subscribe
you know your father the wrists are
working too hard when you get to the
100k
buy your father the rolex watches go for
risk